Guide to the Norman A.D. Parlee Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Norman A.D. Parlee papers
1873-1983
1948-1983
SC0313
Parlee, Norman A.D., d.1985.
1.5 Linear feet
The bulk of these papers consists of correspondence, memos, proposals, reports, and financial records, 1973-1983, pertaining to his research projects funded by or submitted to the Center for Materials Research at Stanford University. Other papers include correspondence, memos, notes, papers, course materials, reports, reprints, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia, 1873-1983, pertaining to the history of metallurgy, teaching, the Dominion Steel and Coal Corp., publications, and a business trip to Europe in 1949.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of the estate of Norman A.D. Parlee, 1985.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Parlee was professor of metallurgy in the Dept. of Mineral Engineering at Stanford University from 1962 until his retirement in 1982; he was professor emeritus until his death in 1985. A graduate of Dalhousie and McGill Universities, Parlee began his career as a research metallurgist at Dominion Steel and Coal Corp. in 1939. He left industry in 1952 to join the faculty at Purdue University. He was a fellow of the Chemical Institute of Canada and the American Institute of Chemistry.
Description of the Collection
The bulk of these papers consists of correspondence, memos, proposals, reports, and financial records, 1973-1983, pertaining to his research projects funded by or submitted to the Center for Materials Research at Stanford University. Other papers include correspondence, memos, notes, papers, course materials, reports, reprints, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia, 1873-1983, pertaining to the history of metallurgy, teaching, the Dominion Steel and Coal Corp., publications, and a business trip to Europe in 1949.
Access Terms
Dominion Steel and Coal Corp.; Parlee, Norman A.D., d.1985.; Stanford University. Center for Materials Research.; Stanford University. School of Engineering. Faculty..; Metallurgical research.; Metallurgy --Study and teaching.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1873-1983; Accession ARCH-1984-127
  - Historical papers regarding Science and Steel Industry, 1944-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Booklets on Iron and Steel Industry and Metal Working, 1873-circa 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parlee Resumé, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum and Course, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum and Course, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Earth Science Faculty, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Book Authorship, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Book Authorship, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - O.F. History (Stone), Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - O.F. History (Stone), Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - O.F. History (Stone), Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - O.F. History (Stone), Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mementoes of European Trip, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mementoes of European Trip, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CMR-ARPA "Calculation of Equilibrium and Transport Properties" Proposal, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - CMR-NSF "Calculation of Equilibrium and Transport Properties" Proposal, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CMR "Nitride-Forming Reactions" Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CMR "Nitride Precipitation Recovery" Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CMR "Carbothemic and Carbo-Nitrothemic Reduction" Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CMR "Carbothemic Reduction" Proposal, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CMR Preliminary Research Programs Information, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CMR Proposal Forms and Rules, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CMR Proposal for Production of Reactive Metals, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - CMR "Calculation of Diffusivities" Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CMR "Zirconium" Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CMR "Hydride Precipitation" Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - CMR Equipment Proposal, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - CMR Instructions for Proposals, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - CMR Research Grant Request for M. Hassan, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - CMR Hydryding Proposal, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - CMR Hydride and Nitride Proposal, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - CMR "Non-Crystalline Metals" Proposal, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - CMR "Production of Volatile Reactive Metals" Proposal, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - CMR "Reactive Metals and Nitrides" Proposal, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - CMR Nitride Proposals, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CMR Proposals, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CMR "Physico-Chemical Study of Titanium" Proposal, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CMR Facilities Brochure, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - CMR General Correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CMR Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - CMR Annual Reports, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CMR Budget and Account Numbers, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - CMR Financial Statements, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - CMR Financial Statements, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - CMR Funding Allocations, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - CMR Funding Awards, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - CMR Grant Extension, 1979 Summer (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - CMR Nuggets, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - CMR "Super-Nugget", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Westinghouse, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - CMR -- Geballe's Westinghouse Trip, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - CMR-NSF THRUST Program, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)